# Harita Chaudhari

860-004-4048 | chaudhariharita[at]gmail.com | Pune LinkedIn: harita-chaudhari

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer with 3+ years of experience, a Master's in Computer Science, and a passion for developing Multi-Cloud SaaS Platforms. Proficient in Java, AWS, Kubernetes, and Databases with a track record of efficiently addressing critical customer issues. Ready to join and contribute immediately.

#### **SKILLS**

- Java (Spring, Spring Boot)
- AWS (S3, EC2)
- Kubernetes
- Kafka
- Redis

- MySQL
- REST API
- MongoDB
- Git
- Cassandra

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Member of Technical Staff, VMware Bangalore

Jul 2020 - Dec 2022

- Developed new features and solved major customer issues using Java (Spring Boot) and Ruby in the SaaS-based platform, while mainly working on integrating VMware Cloud with the platform to manage and analyze customers' overall cloud spending, suggest ways to minimize the costs, display daily/monthly usage costs incurred, etc.
- Worked on Kubernetes to manage the deployment of microservices that were part of the product
- Minimized and solved customer defects to increase customer satisfaction/retention
- Provided on-call support to the team for troubleshooting critical incidents

#### R&D Intern, VMware

Aug 2019 - Apr 2020

- Involved in the development and testing of VMware Integration Validation cloud service, used by VMware partners to certify or validate their software and hardware solutions for integration with VMware technologies
- Improved the overall automation test suite success rate to 95%

# Associate Application Developer, Accenture

Oct 2017 - Jul 2018

 Worked on OpenText StreamServe Platform, to generate PDF and email format bills essential for the client

# **EDUCATION**

# M. Tech. in Computer Science Engineering

VIT Chennai, Vellore University

June 2020

# B.E. in Information Technology

MIT Pune, Pune University

June 2017

#### **PROJECTS**

# A Supervised Learning Framework for Sentiment Analysis on Amazon Product Reviews

Analyzed Amazon product reviews using various Machine learning algorithms and found one efficient algorithm to categorize the review comment as Good/Bad/Neutral.